George Chen

Junior Software Developer

Brooklyn, NY 11228 (917) 889-1891

georgechen1338@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/georgechen1338/ https://georgechen.netlify.app/

PROJECTS

Whack a Diglett(03/22) — Front-end game made with JavaScript, HTML and CSS. Custom take on Whack-a-mole.

Backrub.Wiki(04/22) - 3 person group project, created a website that was an API of tech articles from the NYT for the last 20 years. Front-end made with React and back-end made with MongoDB/Heroku.

Hater.rip(05/22) — Group project where we made a clone of Twitter using React as the front-end and Django, MySQL for a deployed back-end.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, New York, NY Software Engineering Immersive Fellow February 2022 - May 2022

- Completed industry-leading Software Engineering Immersive program focusing on 480+ hours of full-stack web development
- Created 4 web apps in various coding languages and frameworks, such as HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React and Python
- Deployed databases and data structures using MongoDB, Heroku, Django, Flask, PostgreSQL and MySQL.
- Learned to work both as a solo developer and in a group environment with fellow cohort members.

Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center - RARC, New York, NY Animal Research Technician
March 2019 - March 2020

- Provided routine care of research animals.
- Administered medications (pills, injections) as instructed.
- Maintained records in an organized and up-to-date manner.
- Assisted in ensuring compliance with regulatory requirements related to care of laboratory animals.
- Communicated data to all NYULMC staff as needed.

SKILLS

HTML
CSS
JavaScript
Python NodeJS
Express
MongoDB
PostgreSQL
MySQL
Heroku
Flask
Adobe Photoshop

LANGUAGES

Cantonese - Fluent

Mandarin - Conversational

EDUCATION

General Assembly, New York, NY Software Engineering Immersive February 2022 - May 2022

CUNY Hunter College, New York, NY *Bachelor of Arts, Psychology* September 2013 - June 2016